# **Christophe Foyer**

christophe@cfoyer.com • www.cfoyer.com
United States: (+1) 816-419-6150 • France: (+33) 6 78 56 99 03
French and US citizenships; Eligible to work without restriction in the USA and EEA

# **Summary:**

Mechanical Engineering graduate with experience in projects in mechatronics, software, and aerospace engineering. Demonstrated track record of finding creative solutions to engineering challenges while operating under tight budgets.

• CAD, FEA and CFD

• Fabrication (metals, plastics, and composites)

• Electrical System Design

• Linux Server Management and Software Development

#### **Education:**

## **Washington University in Saint Louis**

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering; Minor in Energy Engineering

• Dean's List (Fall 2014, Fall 2017)

Saint Louis, United States Aug 2014 – Dec 2017 3.14/4.00 GPA

**RWTH Aachen** 

'Renewable Energy Technology' | 'Mechatronics and Product Innovation'

**School for International Training** 

Study abroad in Renewable Energy Engineering and Resource Economics

Lycée Sainte Marie

Série S (Science specialization)

• French Baccalauréat: "Mention Bien" (with honors)

Aachen, Germany

Jun 2017 – Jul 2017 Reykjavik, Iceland

Jun 2015 – Aug 2015 Caen, France

Sep 2010 – Jul 2013

# **Relevant Experience:**

#### **Tata Steel Europe**

Mechanical Engineering Intern

Ijmuiden, Netherlands Apr 2018 – July 2018

- Mechanical Engineering Intern
- Built and implemented a real-time temperature simulation of a great number of steel slabs.
- Creation of a modular software framework and implementation of a heat transport model coded in Python.
- Performance optimization for real-time processing and visualization for large datasets.

#### Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly Competition Team

Co-Founder and Systems Team Lead

Treasurer

Washington University in St. Louis, USA

Mar 2016 – Dec 2017

Aug 2016 – May 2017

- Co-led the team to 12<sup>th</sup> place out of 138 teams at the AIAA DBF 2017 competition, and 1<sup>st</sup> in the US Midwest
- Designed aircraft internal system including battery and motor selection with the systems team
- Managed an operating budget of \$10,000 to buy supplies and organize travel to the competition
- Scheduled weekly meetings with the team and set project deadlines

#### **American Society of Mechanical Engineers**

Washington University in St. Louis, USA Sep 2016 – May 2017

Event Planner

• Assisted ASME members with ongoing projects by advising them on manufacturing and component selection

• Researched potential STEM-related speakers to fit within budget constraint, presented reasons to fund Michio Kaku's visit to campus, and secured a date for his visit

#### **Skills and Abilities:**

CAD / FEA / CFD: SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, Autodesk Nettfab, XFLR5

Programming Languages: Matlab, Simulink, Python, Arduino C (C/C++), HTML

Fabrication: 3D-Printing (FDM), Machining (Lathe, Mill), Composite Manufacturing

Software: Microsoft Office Suite, SVN, Windows, Linux

Languages: Bilingual French / English; Basic German and Icelandic

## **Academic Projects:**

#### Senior Design Project – Low-Cost CPV

Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Foyer, Christophe; Rangwala, Adam; and Nana, Deep, "Water Lenses for Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics" (2017). Mechanical Engineering Design Project Class. (https://openscholarship.wustl.edu/mems411/71/)

- Coding of FEA and ray tracing software for optics simulation in MATLAB
- Development of a sunlight tracking circuit and coding using Arduino
- Creation of a working proof of concept prototype increasing solar cell output by 860%.

## **Independent Projects:**

#### **Printable Folding Tricopter**

Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Design of a folding tricopter frame for FDM printing:

- Design of interlocking printable parts using Solidworks and Autodesk Nettfab to be 3D-printed
- Designed to minimize weight and exterior volume while maximizing payload space.

**Motor Test Stand** Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Design and construction of a motor test stand for Wash. U Design/Build/Fly:

- GUI development, serial communication protocol and sensor integration
- Coded in Python and Arduino C, packaged in .exe format for easy deployment to new Windows installations
- Measures motor-propeller-battery system RPM, current, voltage, and thrust and logs output to CSV

Oct 2016 - Dec 2017 **Electric Longboard** 

Design and construction of a custom built electric longboard for daily usage and international travel:

- CAD, FEA, and part fabrication in aluminum and FDM printing of plastic parts
- Electrical powertrain design including component selection balancing efficiency and cost
- Designed according to air travel and personal transportation regulations.

#### **Naïve Bayes Classifier**

Jun 2016 – Aug 2016

Coding of a Naïve Bayes Classifier for financial forecasting using machine learning:

- Average accuracy of 67% on pima-indians-diabetes test dataset.
- Achieved an accuracy of 51.51% when tasked to forecast wheat price trends (low accuracy due to limitations with regards to dataset size; which is a different, ongoing project)

#### **IRIS Voice Recognition and Home Automation**

Jan 2015 – May 2017

Custom-built smart home and media center system:

- Voice recognition using google API interfacing with connected microphones
- Coded in Python 2.7 on a Raspberry Pi running a Linux-based OS (added support for Windows and OSX)
- Control over house appliances (both wired an wirelessly) and interfacing with Open Source Media Center

**Robotics Test Platform** Dec 2013 – Jan 2015

Design, coding, and construction of an internet-controlled robot used for autonomous sensing and navigation testing:

- Coded in Python on Linux-based microcontrollers
- Frontend: webpage coding in HTML and UI design
- Backend: hardware interfacing and communication over WebSocket between the webserver and the local microcontroller.
- Experiments in visual odometry using OpenCV and ROS (ongoing)

# **Volunteering and Work Experience:**

Ishinomaki, Japan **ICC** May 2014 Volunteer

Construction of two wooden terraces for the local community in a region devastated by the 2011 tsunami.

Domaine du Vivier Seasonal farm hand

Le Mesnil Mauger, France Jun 2015 – Aug 2017

Maintenance and operation of farming equipment and various agricultural work

Driver for the tossing of the hay and the loading of hay bales during the summer